In classical embryology, we talk about three
古典的な発生学では、組織について3つの組織が語られます。
tissues.
組織。
Ecto, endo, meso.
外胚葉、内胚葉、中胚葉。
In histology, we talk about two tissues,
組織学では、2つの組織が語られ、
and we could summarize these histological tissues into two main types of tissues.
これらの組織学的組織は、大きく2つのタイプに要約できます。
Epithelial tissues of ectodermal origin,
外胚葉由来の上皮組織、
epithelial tissues of endodermal origin,
内胚葉由来の上皮組織、
In other words, epithelial tissues of neurological origin,
言い換えれば、神経由来の上皮組織、
epithelial tissues of digestive origin, or
消化器由来の上皮組織、または
here, connective tissues, of mesodermal origin.
ここでは、中胚葉由来の結合組織、結合組織。
I have added here a layer that begins to enter
ここに、ブレックミットのプロセスに入り始める層を追加しました。
into the Blechmit process, two qualities of tissue on a plane of
動きの平面上での2つの組織の質、そしてそれは合流します...
In fact, a bit of histology.
実際、少し組織学に似ています。
Finally, he says, I have boundary tissue,
結局、彼は言います、「私には境界組織がある」と。
or what he calls frontier tissue,
あるいは彼が境界組織と呼ぶもの、
or I have interior tissue,
あるいは私には内部組織がある、
what he calls connective tissue.
彼が結合組織と呼ぶもの。
He says, boundary tissue is always ectoderm and endoderm,
彼は言います、境界組織は常に外胚葉と内胚葉であり、
and interior tissue is always mesoderm.
そして内部組織は常に中胚葉であると。
When I use red, in general,
私が赤を使うとき、一般的に、
I will always draw what is representative of the endoderm.
私は常に内胚葉を表すものを描きます。
or more specifically of the
またはより具体的には、消化器系。
digestive system. When I use
消化器系。私が青を使うとき、
blue,
青を使うとき、
I will essentially use the
私は主に外胚葉組織を使います。
ectodermal tissue. When I use
私が主に中胚葉組織を使うとき、
essentially mesodermal,
主に中胚葉組織を使うとき、
which comes and which I study,
それが来て、私が研究し、
and I see, oh, I'm on an artery.
そして私は、ああ、動脈の上にいることに気づきます。
Well, for me,
ええと、私の場合、
in my head, it immediately goes,
私の頭の中では、すぐに、
it's an artery, a mesoderm,
それは動脈、中胚葉、
interior tissue. I know
内部組織です。私は自分がシステム内のどこにいるかを知っています。
where I am in the system.
私は自分がシステム内のどこにいるかを知っています。
So I recognize a dynamic,
だから私はダイナミクスを認識し、
already, it allows me to orient myself.
すでに、それは私に自分の位置を特定することを可能にします。
This is the link between histology,
これは組織学、
embryology
発生学、
and biodynamic embryology.
そして生体力学的発生学の間のつながりです。
Well, it's a bit of a representation
ええと、これは少し
of the tissue
組織の
ectodermal, epithelial.
外胚葉性、上皮性の表現です。
It's the ectoderm, meaning
これは外胚葉、つまり
it's a tissue
これは組織です
that is concentrated
集中している
between a liquid
液体と
and an interior tissue.
内部組織の間です。
Here, I have the sea, and
ここに海があり、
in the center, between the two, I have an interior tissue, and
中央には、その間に内部組織があり、
below, I have the Mediterranean,
下には地中海があります。
a mesodermal tissue, an endodermal tissue, also concentrated,
中胚葉組織、内胚葉組織も集中しており、
we often see near
よく見かけるのは
the sea, like that, you see, a concentration. And so here, what
海辺で、このように、ほら、集中しています。それで、ここで何が
do we see? It will
見えるでしょうか？これは
explain to us the characteristics of these tissues, that the boundary tissue, excuse me,
これらの組織の特性を説明してくれます。つまり、境界組織は、失礼、
is always located between what we call the fluid and
常に液体と
the interior tissue. If we
内部組織の間に位置しています。鼓膜を
observe the eardrum, it is made of three tissues. It is made of ectodermal tissue, on
観察すると、3つの組織でできています。外側の
the outside,
外胚葉組織と、
inside, it is made of tissue.
内側は組織でできています。
The endodermal tissue, and in the middle, it is made of
内胚葉組織、そして真ん中は
mesodermal tissue.
中胚葉組織でできています。
The frontier tissue, therefore the boundary tissue,
したがって、境界組織、つまり限界組織は、
is always dependent on the interior tissue.
常に内部組織に依存しています。
In other words, epithelial tissue is always
言い換えれば、上皮組織は常に
dependent on connective tissue.
結合組織に依存しています。
because the vessels and nourishment come from the interior
なぜなら、血管と栄養は内部
tissue
組織から来て、
and is distributed in the frontier tissue.
境界組織に分配されるからです。
So, in other words, it is the mesodermal tissue
つまり、中胚葉組織が
that contains the trophic information for growth and maintenance
成長と成長の維持に関する栄養情報を
of growth.
含んでいるのです。
Much more serious than here.
ここよりもはるかに深刻です。
There is no congestion in the boundary tissue.
境界組織にはうっ血は存在しません。
but that there can be phases of congestion
しかし、内部組織にはうっ血の段階が
in the interior tissue.
存在する可能性があります。
Take these tissues and you realize
これらの組織を取って、あなたは気づくでしょう
that there is a dried area.
乾燥した領域があることに。
You must rehydrate, reopen, reconnect.
再水和し、再開し、再接続する必要があります。
It can be congestion
それは鬱血かもしれませんし、
or a drying phase.
乾燥期かもしれません。
And in life, that's how it happens.
そして、人生ではそのように起こります。
If you have dryness,
もし乾燥しているなら、
the tissue is completely dry.
組織は完全に乾いています。
If it rains too much, you have phases of congestion.
もしそれが多すぎると、鬱血の段階があります。
And you also have natural phases of congestion.
そして、自然な鬱血の段階もあります。
A woman has natural congestions.
女性には自然な鬱血があります。
every month, she has uterine congestion
毎月、彼女は子宮の鬱血を経験します。
which is a cleansing
それは浄化です。
because she is ready to welcome life
なぜなら、彼女は生命を受け入れる準備ができているからです。
and so what happens, if she cannot welcome
そして、もし彼女が受け入れられない場合、何が起こるでしょうか？
well, the entire glandular system
腺系全体が
shrinks, eliminates itself
縮小し、排除され、
and she moves on to another...
彼女は別の段階へと移行します。
So this corresponds a bit to the campaign
これは少し田舎に対応しています。
it means that this tissue here
つまり、ここのこの組織は
it will give the whole system
システム全体を形成します。
that is to say
つまり、
all my vessels
私のすべての血管、
all my arteries, all my veins
私のすべての動脈、私のすべての静脈、
my whole system
私のシステム全体です。
It will also give the entire skeletal, musculo-
それはまた、骨格系全体、筋骨格系、骨、膜、腹膜も形成します。
skeletal system, bones, membranes, peritoneums, in the
頭蓋骨では、それを相互緊張膜と呼びます。
cranium you will call them reciprocal tension membranes.
循環器系全体、泌尿生殖器系全体、そして
The entire circulatory system, the entire urogenital system and the entire
支持系全体は中胚葉組織、言い換えれば
support system, it is mesodermal tissue or in other
中胚葉組織です。
words it is mesodermal tissue.
境界組織には多種多様な形態が見られます。
we find a great variety of forms in the boundary tissue,
それは表面成長であり、鬱血の段階はなく、
these are surface growths, there is no congestion phase
多くの細胞があります。それは常に内部組織に依存しています。
and there are
一方、
many cells. It is always dependent on the interior tissue,
内部組織は、2つの組織の間にあります。
whereas
では、私が顔に良いパンチを受けたとしましょう。
the interior tissue, it is between the two tissues. Let's assume
私は屁をこき、出会いをします。ほら、圧力がかかり、
now
そして私は内部組織を取り除きます。
that I receive a good blow to the face.
私の陣営には何がありますか？
I fart, I make a connection, you see, the pressure is made,
もう液体はありません。
There is no more liquid, I lose the interior tissue.
もう液体はありません。内部の組織を失っています。
Okay?
いいですか？
For example, two vessels meeting.
例えば、2つの血管が出会う場合。
You see, the tissue, the tissue.
組織、組織を見てください。
I lose my interior tissue, I have a corrosion field.
内部の組織を失い、腐食の場があります。
In a very simplified way, I
非常に簡略化して言えば、
see that all the constituents of connective tissue are
結合組織のすべての構成要素は、
summarized in these four major components.
これら4つの主要な構成要素に要約されていることがわかります。
Now, if I take a tissue and
さて、もし私が組織を取り、
I'm going to put a bone here, a muscle.
ここに骨、筋肉を置くとします。
I'm going to compare them. In a bone, there are many cells. However,
それらを比較してみましょう。骨には多くの細胞があります。しかし、
I have little water or minerals.
水やミネラルは少ないです。
And there, in the fibers, what will I have in a bone or collagen
そして、線維の中には、骨やコラーゲンの中に何があるでしょうか？
?
？
If I take a muscle, I have a few less cells,
筋肉を取ると、細胞は少し少なく、
I have a little more water.
水は少し多いです。
At the matrix level, there is a change.
マトリックスのレベルでは変化があります。
At the fiber level, I have more elastic.
線維のレベルでは、より弾力性があります。
Now, if we go a little further,
さて、もう少し深く掘り下げてみましょう。
we have what are called glycosaminoglycans.
グリコサミノグリカンと呼ばれるものがあります。
I enter into this matrix process.
このマトリックスプロセスに入ります。
And what do I observe?
そして、何に気づくでしょうか？
That I either have a structure that is permeable,
透過性のある構造、つまりむしろ脱重合した構造か、
that is to say, rather depolymerized,
つまりむしろ脱重合した構造か、
or I have a structure that is rather...
あるいはむしろ...
dense, which is therefore dense, which is hard, where I have
密な、つまり密で硬い構造で、
what is called a polymerized structure.
重合した構造と呼ばれるものがあります。
What is the densest structure in the body?
体の中で最も密な構造は何ですか？
The dense one.
密な。
We will say the ligaments, the ligaments, then
靭帯、靭帯、そして
we will say the tendons.
腱と言いましょう。
And then we'll put the blood up to here.
そして、ここまで血液を入れましょう。
We'll go that far.
そこまで行きましょう。
We can put all the mesodermal type structures here.
ここにすべての中胚葉型の構造を置くことができます。
And I simply observe that it is either permeable or
そして、それが透過性であるか、あるいは
it is viscous.
粘性であるかのどちらかであることに気づきます。
And if I go that way, I go towards something fluid.
そして、もし私がそちらに行けば、流動的なものに向かいます。
That way, what am I going towards?
そちらに行けば、何に向かうでしょうか？
constraints
制約
the observation of teeth
歯の観察
the observation of occlusion
咬合の観察は
gives you
あなたに与えます
the perfect image
完璧なイメージを
of the constraints
制約の
that are found at the level of the sphenobasilar symphysis
それは蝶形骨と後頭骨の結合部にあります
and we will see
そして、私たちは見るでしょう
that this sphenobasilar symphysis
この蝶形骨と後頭骨の結合部が
in embryology
発生学において
it's a key
鍵であると
for the body
体にとって
it's as if
まるで
I could call it the zero point
私はそれをゼロ点と呼ぶことができます
a point
一点
neutral that receives
体のすべての情報を受け取る中立点
all the information of the body
体のすべての情報を受け取る
whether on the vascular level
血管系であろうと
lymphatic
リンパ系であろうと
whether on the neurological level
神経系であろうと
digestive
消化器系であろうと
tension membrane etc.
緊張膜など
the sphenobasilar symphysis is aware
蝶形骨と後頭骨の結合部は知っています
of everything that happens
起こっていることすべてを
and the teeth will always
そして歯は常に
manage as best they can
できる限り対処します
If they have to grind their teeth or do anything
歯ぎしりをしたり、何でもする必要があるなら
to give freedom
自由を与えるために
at those levels.
これらのレベルで。
And the base of the teeth, the occlusion,
そして歯の基部、咬合、
the teeth, they are posture sensors.
歯は姿勢のセンサーです。
It means
それは意味します
that it is a very important relationship
非常に重要な関係があることを
between the teeth and the notochord.
歯と脊索の間には。
Or more precisely,
あるいはもっと正確に言えば、
it is a very important relationship
非常に重要な関係があります
between the teeth
歯と
and the entire vertebral axis.
脊椎全体の間には。
Or in other words,
あるいは別の言葉で言えば、
the teeth can
歯は
can disturb the statics.
静力学を乱す可能性があります。
In other words, a herniated disc can be treated by rebalancing the occlusion.
言い換えれば、椎間板ヘルニアは咬合を再調整することで治療できる可能性があります。
The teeth, they are the ones that can take the constraints,
歯は、ストレスを受けることができるものです。
they are the ones that carry the karmic burden of your life.
それはあなたの人生のカルマ的な重荷を背負っています。
Health is a balance, we talked about it, in
健康とはバランスであり、私たちはそれについて話しました。
this dynamic.
このダイナミクスの中で。
It is a harmony that will express a state of well-being.
それは良い状態を表現する調和です。
etc. Let's take a tendon. I have a tendon. Which,
など。腱を取り上げましょう。私には腱があります。それは、
if it is free in its good dynamic,
もしそれがその良いダイナミクスの中で自由であれば、
there is no problem, it is in its good network, it is in a good balance
問題はありません。それはその良いネットワークの中にあり、良いバランスの中にあります。
between the
の間で、
constraint and the fluids. It is in balance and in a fair
ストレスと体液。それはバランスの中にあり、そして公正な、
exchange of trophic information,
栄養情報の交換、
it receives. But now, it happens that there is an imbalance
それは受け取ります。しかし今、不均衡が生じています。
which can be internal.
それは内部的なものである可能性があります。
or an imbalance coming from outside due to a profession,
あるいは、職業によって外部から来る不均衡、
well, all of a sudden, the tendon loses its quality of place.
すると突然、腱はその場所の質を失います。
And what does it do? It has more constraints.
そして、それは何をしますか？それはより多くのストレスを抱えます。
And so, it goes that way.
そして、それはそちらへ向かいます。
And so, what does it receive in its metabolism?
では、その代謝において何を受け取っているのでしょうか？
A change of information.
情報の変化。
This will lead to what is called calcifying tendinitis.
それは石灰化腱炎と呼ばれるものにつながります。
And what happens when I have calcifying tendinitis?
そして、石灰化腱炎になったとき、何が起こるのでしょうか？
The bone, I harden, you see, and
骨が硬くなり、ほら、そして、
I catch here.
ここで捕まります。
Because we will see in detail that the limbs are an expansion of a peritoneal sac,
なぜなら、手足は腹膜嚢の拡張であることを詳しく見ていくからです。
pleurocardio-peritoneal, you see, in a specific movement.
胸膜心膜腹膜、ほら、特定の動きの中で。
It will happen at the same time as this movement happens here, you see.
この動きがここで起こるのと同時に、それは起こります、ほら。
The result of your sphere here, the elbow, the wrist, we will find it in the body like that.
ここにあるあなたの球体、肘、手首の結果は、体の中でこのように見つかります。
I have hepatosis or I have a pulmonary deficit or something else, it can block
肝臓病や肺機能の低下などがあると、それがブロックされる可能性があります。
my system
私のシステム
of rotation here and express itself at a distance here. So sometimes what happens here
ここでの回転が、遠く離れたここで表現されることがあります。だから、ここで起こることが、
can be the expression
表現である可能性があります。
of an imbalance that happens here. Through this study of embryology, it will give us
ここで起こる不均衡の。この発生学の研究を通して、それは私たちに、
what we
私たちが呼ぶもの、
call the links and interactions of tissues. Allostasis is
組織のつながりと相互作用。アロスタシスとは、
the processes that allow
ホメオスタシスを維持するためのプロセスです。
to rebalance this, so it's all the processes and for that I need
これを再調整するために、すべてのプロセスが必要です。そのためには、
a magnetic force, I need an electricity, a voltage
磁力が必要です。電気、電圧が必要です。
we even measured, it's a Swiss biologist friend who measured on the
私たちは測定さえしました。スイスの生物学者の友人が、
membrane the electrical forces in the glycocalyx that were expressed so
グリコカリックス内の電気力を測定しました。
on this
その
electrical network, it's enormous in fact that we're going to go into this perception, we're
電気的なネットワークは、私たちがこの知覚に入っていくとき、実際には巨大です。
going to work with a microcrystalline field
私たちは微結晶場を使って作業します。
If we are going to go into this force of perception at the level of the embryo,
もし私たちが胚のレベルでこの知覚の力に入っていくなら、
we must refine certain notions here and certain notions here.
私たちはここでいくつかの概念を、そしてここでいくつかの概念を洗練しなければなりません。
You will see that the touch is extremely gentle.
触診が非常に優しいことがわかるでしょう。
When I touch someone, people tell me, it's very gentle.
私が誰かに触れると、人々は「とても優しい」と言います。
And at the same time, we feel that it's very global, if you will.
そして同時に、それが非常に全体的であると感じられます。
Because I work on this microcrystalline field.
なぜなら、私はこの微結晶場に取り組んでいるからです。
We will see that the hand comes to rest in its formation on the heart.
手が心臓の上に形成されるように置かれることがわかるでしょう。
That your eyes...
あなたの目が...
rests on the heart
心臓の上に置かれる
and that your voice
そしてあなたの声が
and that the heart emits a rhythmic field
そして心臓はリズミカルな場を発している
already on the 23rd day
すでに23日目には
very powerful
非常に強力な
which informs
情報を伝える
in a pulsatile way
拍動的に
you see
わかるでしょう
and in a rhythmic way
そしてリズミカルに
and in an electrical way
そして電気的に
your hands
あなたの手は
it means that you are informed
心臓のリズムによってすでに情報を受け取っている
already by the rhythm of the heart
あなたの視線でさえも
even in your gaze.
あなたの視線でさえも。
And it happens at the level of the thyroid.
そしてそれは甲状腺のレベルで起こります。
The thyroid comes from the tongue,
甲状腺は舌から来ており、
and the tongue is the bud of the heart.
舌は心臓の芽です。
You see?
わかるでしょう？
It's when I speak, at 7 years old,
私が話すとき、7歳で、
my sinus opens,
私の副鼻腔が開きます。
at the same time that my thyroid becomes completely active
同時に私の甲状腺が完全に活動的になります。
on the vibratory level.
振動のレベルで。
You see?
わかるでしょう？
And that's why at 7, I can stand up for myself.
だからこそ、7歳で私は立ち向かうことができます。
I can start to defend myself with words.
私は自分自身で身を守り始めることができます。
word. Before that,
言葉で。それ以前は、
I fought,
私は戦っていました。
children, they fight before. And then at some point,
子供たちは以前は戦います。そしてある時点で、
they reach the age of reason.
彼らは理性の時代にいます。
Hey, I can talk.
ほら、話せるようになった。
Because all of a sudden, I receive my strength
なぜなら、突然、私はここで力を受け取るからだ
here, in words.
言葉の中に。
I can start to reason with my head.
頭で推論し始めることができる。
That's the song of the heart.
それが心の歌だ。
That's what will be expressed.
それが表現されるものだ。
it's a movement
それは動きです
of the sphenoid
蝶形骨の
in connection
関連して
with the upper maxilla.
上顎骨と。
The occiput is fixed, the jaw
後頭骨は固定され、顎は
remains fixed. This gives
固定されたままです。それは
a twisting movement.
ねじれの動きを生み出します。
Look at the position of the teeth.
歯の位置を見てください。
We sometimes find
私たちは見つけます
this kind of thing in patients.
患者によっては、このようなことが時々あります。
Cross-articulated.
関節が交差している。
Now, in the image of a
さて、あるイメージの中で
What we call a side bending, look, at
いわゆるサイドベンディング、見てください、
the level of the occiput, look carefully, this time occiput, side bending, rotation,
後頭骨のレベルで、よく見てください、今回は後頭骨、サイドベンディング、回転、
look what happens at the level of my sphenobasilar symphysis, look, you
私の蝶形後頭骨結合のレベルで何が起こるか見てください、見てください、あなたは
saw, look what happens at the level of the face, one eye smaller,
見ましたか、顔のレベルで何が起こるか見てください、片方の目がより
one eye larger, look, nasion, look at the position of the jaws.
小さく、もう片方の目がより大きく、見てください、鼻骨、顎の位置を見てください。
Look this time at the link between the upper maxilla and the lower maxilla.
今回は上顎と下顎の間のつながりを見てください。
Look at the image of the strains.
ストリングスの画像を見てください。
Cervical strains, upper, lower strains.
頸部ストリングス、上部ストリングス、下部ストリングス。
Look what happens at that level.
そのレベルで何が起こるか見てください。
Look at someone who has prognathism or retrognathism.
下顎前突症または下顎後退症の患者を見てください。
This is the introduction.
これが導入です。
that we will put
私たちが置くもの
in the future establishment
将来の配置において
of the notochordal axis
脊索軸の
with the future development of the sacrum
仙骨の将来の発展とともに
and the axis
そして軸の
primitive cranio-sacral.
原始的な頭蓋仙骨。
That is to say, when we touch
つまり、私たちが触れるとき
a sacrum, it has the history of all that.
仙骨は、これらすべての歴史を持っています。
And you will see that a sacrum
そして、仙骨が
is a base of the skull,
頭蓋骨の基部であることを見てください、
it makes no difference.
違いはありません。
It's the same thing.
同じことです。
It's the same tissue, it's just a...
同じ組織です。ただの...
movement. We will see in development, the sacrum will be the mobile fulcrum
動きです。発生において、仙骨は可動性の支点となり、
and the base of the
頭蓋の
cranium will be the fulcrum. That's why the sacrum is at the base of cortical
基底部が支点となります。そのため、仙骨は皮質発生の基盤となります。まず、外胚葉について話すとき、私はどの組織について話しているのでしょうか？
development. Firstly, when I talk about ectoderm, what tissue am I talking about
皮質。まず、外胚葉について話すとき、私はどの組織について話しているのでしょうか？
?
？
1,360. I will keep your notes if necessary. What tissue am I talking about when we talk about ectoderm,
1,360。必要であれば、あなたのメモを取っておきます。外胚葉について話すとき、私はどの組織について話しているのでしょうか？
I am talking about tissue? 1,360. Two limits. On a histological level,
私は組織について話していますか？1,360。2つの限界。組織学的に、
what tissue am I talking about?
私はどの組織について話しているのでしょうか？
Epithelial.
上皮。
And on a structural level,
そして構造的に、
when I talk about ectodermal tissue,
外胚葉組織について話すとき、
I'm talking about your entire nervous system,
私はあなたの神経系全体について話しています。
central,
中枢、
peripheral,
末梢、
and the skin around it.
そして周囲の皮膚。
So this is viscerocranium.
これは内臓頭蓋です。
This is neurocranium.
これは神経頭蓋です。
One is endodermal,
一方は内胚葉性で、
the other is ectodermal.
もう一方は外胚葉性です。
When I talk to you about the viscerocranium,
内臓頭蓋について話すとき、
it's the face,
それは顔ですが、
but it's up to here.
ここまでです。
All of this is viscerocranium.
これらすべては内臓頭蓋です。
I told you,
私はあなたに話しました、
I remember, in the small table,
覚えています、小さな表で、
I said the interior tissue
私は内部組織と
and the boundary tissue.
境界組織と言いました。
And I said
そして私は言いました、
that one was always
一方は常に
dependent on the other.
もう一方に依存していると。
So the boundary tissue
したがって、境界組織は
is always dependent on the interior tissue.
常に内部組織に依存しています。
In other words,
言い換えれば、
I cannot
私は
talk about the development
神経系の発生について
nervous system, without its wrapping, which is
その包装なしには話すことができません。
its mesodermal system, or in other
その中胚葉系、つまり別の言い方をすれば、
words, which will be all the tension membranes, or in other words, which will be
それはすべての張力膜、つまり別の言い方をすれば、
the dura
硬膜の
mater, and its entire system around it.
膜、そしてその周りのすべてのシステム。
I cannot talk about it, I cannot separate them in development.
それについて話すことはできません。発生においてそれらを分離することはできません。
Same thing, I cannot talk to you about the digestive tract.
同様に、消化管について話すことはできません。
without talking to you about the peritoneum.
腹膜について話さずに。
But the peritoneum is not endoderm, it is mesoderm.
しかし、腹膜は内胚葉ではなく、中胚葉です。
Okay?
いいですか？
So, I can't do both.
だから、両方を行うことはできません。
It means that when I talk about the ectoderm,
つまり、外胚葉について話すとき、
I will always talk to you about the ectomesoderm
常に外中胚葉について話します。
or the endomesoderm.
または内中胚葉について。
Okay?
いいですか？
Because they are linked, they function like that.
なぜなら、それらは関連しており、そのように機能しているからです。
However, when I talk to you purely about the mesoderm,
一方、純粋に中胚葉について話すとき、
I will talk to you about the mesoderm, with the mesoderm.
中胚葉について、中胚葉とともに話します。
It's that the base of the skull, already like that,
それは、頭蓋底がすでにそのように、
is a balance between my neurocranium and my viscerocranium.
私の神経頭蓋と私の内臓頭蓋の間のバランスです。
I have mesoderm, that is to say, I have cartilaginous tissue and then bone tissue.
私は中胚葉、つまり軟骨組織と骨組織を持っています。
The ectoblast will give all the nervous tissue and the skin.
外胚葉はすべての神経組織と皮膚を与えます。
The mesoblast will give you everything that is skeletal, muscles, connective tissues, circulatory systems.
中胚葉は、骨格、筋肉、結合組織、循環器系など、すべてのものを提供します。
and everything that is
そして、すべてのもの
renal or urogenital,
腎臓または泌尿生殖器、
everything that is endoblast,
すべての内胚葉、
all the digestive glands,
すべての消化腺、
all the digestive epithelium and all the epithelium
すべての消化器上皮とすべての呼吸器
respiratory.
上皮。
Your respiratory system,
あなたの呼吸器系は、
is actually endoderm.
実際には内胚葉です。
It's the same tissue as the
それは、元のレベルでは、消化器
digestive tissue, at the original level.
組織と同じ組織です。
And they support each other
そして、それらは互いに完全に
completely in
その機能において支え合っています。言い換えれば、人間は
their function. In other
人間は内臓頭蓋であり、それは外胚葉に対応し、または上皮組織、
words, a man does not take back
または境界組織に対応します。
The viscerocranial man corresponds to the ectoderm, or to the epithelial
人間は内臓頭蓋であり、それは内胚葉であり、したがってすべての消化器系であり、
tissue, or to the boundary tissue.
すべての消化器系であり、すべての
The viscerocranial man is the endoderm, so it's the entire digestive system, it's
上皮系です。
And the internal man, the mesodermal type man, corresponds to the entire
そして、内部の人間、中胚葉型の人間は、すべての
support system, the entire bone system,
支持システム、すべての骨格システム、
the entire musculoskeletal system, the entire system.
すべての筋骨格系、すべてのシステム。
the urogenital, the entire internal circulatory system.
泌尿生殖器系、すべての内部循環系。
The support tissue, that means the interior tissue,
支持組織とは、内部の組織、
the tissue that informs the body.
身体を形作る組織を意味します。
So we will see that we can define the embryo in terms of days.
したがって、胚を日数で定義できることがわかります。
We can also talk about Carnegie stages.
カーネギーについても話すことができます。
I will talk to you in days.
日数でお話しします。
When there are synchronicities of phenomena,
現象の同期性がある場合、
like the closure of the neuropores,
神経孔の閉鎖のように、
with the integration of these somites and things like that,
これらのラウムの統合などとともに、
we would give you the time.
時間を与えます。
At the moment of the heart's awakening,
心臓の意識の瞬間に、
we would give precise points.
正確なポイントを与えます。
Otherwise, we will talk about days or weeks.
そうでなければ、日数または週数で話します。
And also, we will give some notions of size.
そして、サイズの概念も少し与えます。
What is really important for you,
あなたにとって本当に重要なのは、
is the notion of growth.
成長の概念です。
It's to see that it grows.
それが成長していることを見ることです。
In fact, what you need to understand,
実際、理解すべきことは、
is that it's a developmental movement.
それは発達的な動きであるということです。
In learning.
学習において。
It's a movement that develops like that, but it's not a movement that happens
それはこのように発達する動きですが、それは
like that.
このように行われる動きではありません。
That's the difference between what we call motility and mobility.
それが、運動性（motility）と可動性（mobility）と呼ばれるものの違いです。
One is an embryonic response, that is to say, it follows the movement of
一方は胚の反応であり、つまり、それは
development,
発達の動きに従います。
and the other is a movement purely linked to
そしてもう一方は、純粋に
respiration and which will give movements,
呼吸に関連する動きであり、動きを生み出します。
and the other is a movement still given to motor skills.
そしてもう一方は、運動性（motricity）に与えられた動きです。
You see, you have to make a clear distinction. When I move like this, it's very different from
見てください、違いを明確にする必要があります。このように動くとき、それは私の肝臓の
the movement at the level of my liver.
動きとは非常に異なります。
So if I want to rework a tissue, I give it back its motility.
したがって、組織を再加工したい場合は、その運動性に戻します。
And its functional strength is there. You see, it's
そして、その機能的な力はそこにあります。見てください、
there where it will resume.
そこから回復します。
And that's the work we do, it's to go back into this tissue so that it, okay, I reorganize myself and
そして、それが私たちが行う仕事です。その組織に戻り、それが再編成され、
there I can regain my mobility, my motor skills.
そこで私は可動性、運動性を取り戻すことができます。
Do you understand?
理解できますか？
It's always about following the movement,
常に動きに従うことです。
but here, you need the fulcrums
しかし、そこには支点が必要です。
and to have the movement in your hand.
そして、手に動きを感じること。
I don't treat an organ.
私は臓器を治療するのではありません。
I treat an environment.
私は環境を治療します。
But sometimes, my action can be on
しかし、時には私の行動は
mobility, motor skills.
可動性、運動性に関わることもあります。
And there, in mobility, what is it?
では、可動性とは何でしょうか？
The master of mobility is the diaphragm.
可動性のマスターは横隔膜です。
That's why we're going to learn how this diaphragm is built.
だから、この横隔膜がどのように構築されるかを学ぶのです。
One day, he taught me, he said, Marc, one day, you will feel the power in the tissue.
ある日、彼は私に教えてくれました。「マーク、いつか君は組織の中に力を感じるだろう」と。
For me, power was very intellectual.
私にとって、その力は非常に知的なものでした。
At the same time, intellectually, I tell myself, yes, I can understand that there is a kind of.
同時に、知的であるということは、ある種のものを理解できるということです。
I see an embryo developing, you can imagine the power of the thing.
発生する胚を見ると、その力の凄まじさが想像できます。
It doesn't stop.
それは止まりません。
There's a power, it's crazy.
とんでもない力です。
And he tells me, sometimes,
そして彼は私に言いました、「時には、
In the stimuli, in certain fulcrums, the power is there too, you see, and then, there, you can, something
刺激の中で、特定の支点の中で、その力もそこにあるんだ。わかるかい？そして、そこで、君は、
happens, but you can't create that all the time.
何かが起こるんだが、それをいつも作り出すことはできない。
You have to try to be present, to have a good connection, and then at some point, the system
君は、自分を現在に置き、良い繋がりを持つように努めなければならない。そして、ある時点で、システムは
adjusts, you see.
調整されるんだ。わかるかい？
And then, at some point, he tells me, well, it's as if you were on a small boat in the sea, you see, you
そして、ある時点で、彼は私に言いました。「まるで君が海に浮かぶ小さなボートに乗っているようなものだ。わかるかい？君は
were just in the water, like that, you see.
ただ水の中にいるだけだ。わかるかい？
You don't see it, but beneath you, a whale is coming.
君には見えないが、君の下にはクジラがやってくる。
And you're just there and you feel it.
そして君はただそこにいて、感じるんだ。
You feel it all of a sudden.
突然、すべてを感じる。
It's a bit like that sensation.
少しそのような感覚です。
But look,
しかし、見てください、
first day,
初日、
the little mess that we are,
私たちがいるこの小さな混乱、
and look what will happen
そして何が起こるか見てください
at the end of the second month.
2ヶ月目の終わりに。
Look in two months,
2ヶ月で、
already what is happening.
すでに何が起こっているか見てください。
And look already here,
そして、すでにここを見てください、
beginning of the twentieth day,
20日目の初めには、
a form is already being made.
すでに形ができています。
Here, the potential for life is there.
そこに生命の可能性が存在します。
This is simply an ovum that has received the genetic heritage
これは、父親の遺伝的
of the father,
情報を受け取った卵子、
so the sperm, and the two heritages are busy meeting.
つまり精子であり、両方の遺伝情報が出会おうとしているのです。
This is pretty much the first image of your life.
これはあなたの人生のほぼ最初のイメージです。
This is what is still called the zona pellucida and nurse cells.
これはまだ透明帯と栄養細胞と呼ばれています。
Another important layer of cells.
もう一層の重要な細胞です。
If I take a cell,
もし私が細胞を一つ取り、
and I put my nucleus in the center of the cell, right in the center,
そして核を細胞の中心、まさに中心に置くと、
it is not polarized.
それは分極していません。
I must exchange with whom? With my environment.
私は誰と交換しなければならないのか？私の環境とです。
I must exchange with you.
私はあなたと交換しなければなりません。
Well, if I create here, there, I create a possibility of exchange
さて、もし私がここに、そこに、交換の可能性を作り出すなら、
the same for my entire environment.
私の環境全体も同様です。
However, one image, and that's why, remember,
しかし、一つのイメージ、だから覚えておいてください、
in a cell,
細胞の中では、
In all the cells of your body, the nucleus
あなたの体のすべての細胞において、核は
is never in the center.
決して中心にはありません。
It is always eccentric.
常に偏心しています。
And that is the momentary image of a polarity.
そしてこれは、分極の一時的なイメージです。
Why? Because if I have a cell here with an eccentric nucleus,
なぜか？もし私がここに核が
eccentric,
偏心した細胞を持っているなら、
I have a much more important metabolic activity
ここにはるかに重要な代謝活動が
here.
あります。
And I must have...
そして私は持たなければなりません...
this field of activity
この活動の場を
more important, it increases
より重要に、それは増加させます
the metabolic force.
代謝力を。
And that is the expression
そしてこれは
of polarity.
分極の表現です。
You see?
わかりますか？
We resume at the stage where I am an oocyte.
私が卵母細胞である段階に戻りましょう。
We saw that it had been
それが
polarized by
周囲の小さな細胞によって
small cells around it
分極されていたのを見ましたね。
that had released things, you see,
それらが何かを放出し、
that had created what is called Wolpert's flag,
ウォルパーの旗と呼ばれるものを作り出したのを覚えていますか？
do you remember?
覚えていますか？
Which had created concentrations
それらが私のシステム内で
molecular within the very
分子の、
atomic, within my very system
原子の濃度を作り出し、
which makes it polarized.
それが分極しているのです。
So there is a force, there is a plus,
だから力があり、プラスがあり、
there is a minus.
マイナスがあります。
The sperm, when it arrives,
精子がやってくると、
it comes
それはやってきて
to touch the membrane.
膜に触れます。
We will see in detail, it releases
詳細は後で説明しますが、それは放出します
a hormone called ZP3
ZP3と呼ばれるホルモンを
which is a very specific thing,
それは非常に特殊なものですが、
but very interesting to know
しかし、知っておくと非常に興味深いものです
for later.
後で。
My polarity which is here, inside the embryo, which was
ここにある私の極性、胚の内部にあった私の極性は、
there, it's as if I had a compass, with my north and my south, you see.
そこにあったのは、まるでコンパスを持っているかのようで、北と南がある、わかるでしょう。
Except I don't know where north and south are.
ただ、北と南がどこにあるのかわからないだけです。
It is not oriented in relation to my environment, it is oriented
それは私の環境に対して方向付けられているのではなく、
in relation to my space.
私の空間に対して方向付けられています。
And at the moment the sperm arrives, there is a global reorganization of the parametric system
そして、精子が到着した瞬間、システム全体が再編成されます
parametric.
パラメトリックに。
to space. The electric field reorganizes itself in relation to this level.
空間に対して。電場はこのレベルで再編成されます。
It receives a
それは受け取ります
membrane information, there is a cortical degranulation that occurs inside, so
膜情報、内部で皮質顆粒放出が起こり、
that only one passes. It's an extraordinary encounter, you see,
一つだけが通過できるように。それは並外れた出会いです、わかるでしょう、
between
間に
these two heritages, you see, these two movements. It's always a miracle, you see. And
これら二つの遺産、わかるでしょう、これら二つの動き。それは毎回奇跡です、わかるでしょう。そして
there, all of a sudden, my oocyte is polarized and...
そこで、突然、私の卵母細胞は極性化され、そして...
the meeting of my two heritages will be created.
私の二つの遺産の出会いが生まれます。
This will form a nucleus, a field.
それは核、場を形成します。
And the nucleus, if you will, is on the, so to speak, electrical axis of the system.
そして、核は、言ってみれば、システムの電気的な軸上にあります。
But it corresponds to the fact that it is eccentric.
しかし、それは偏心しているという事実に対応しています。
It's its response to globality.
それは全体性に対するその応答です。
Now, where is the largest electrical field in our body?
さて、私たちの体の中で最大の電場はどこにあるでしょうか？
It's along our spinal column.
それは私たちの脊柱に沿っています。
this is a power
これは力です
from my brain there is a very powerful electric field
私の脳からは非常に強力な電場があります
there is a large electric field at the heart level
心臓のレベルには大きな電場があります
there is a large electric field here
ここには大きな電場があります
but the most important axis is along my spinal column
しかし、最も重要な軸は私の脊柱に沿っています
it's a place of exchange
それは交換の場です
very important right down to your fingertips
指の先まで非常に重要です
but there is a concentration
しかし、集中があります
so we're going to do a practice
だから私たちは練習をします
and we're going to imagine
そして私たちは想像します
that we are just a cell
私たちがただ一つの細胞であると
on the table
テーブルの上に
And we, we're going to come, we're not going to do much.
そして、私たちは、あまり何もしません。
You're just going to put yourself.
あなたは、ただ、身を置くだけです。
One of them will just put themselves at the foot.
一人がただ足元に身を置きます。
You see?
わかる？
Either you go over there, you go a little further down, here.
あなたはあそこに座るか、もう少し下に、ここに座るか。
So someone sits here, but we don't care how we touch.
だから誰かがここに座るんだけど、どう触るかはどうでもいい。
The only thing is that we touch.
唯一のことは、触れること。
You can touch here.
あなたはここに触れてもいい。
The only thing is that we touch gently.
唯一のことは、そっと触れること。
You, you sit there, you take a chair.
あなたはそこに座って、椅子を取って。
You, you take a chair, you sit here.
あなたは椅子を取って、ここに座って。
And we will see in embryology that we start from
そして、私たちは発生学において、私たちが
there and we come back there.
そこから始まり、そこに戻るのを見るでしょう。
It's as if, at some point, we're going to leave, we're in the void,
まるで、ある瞬間、私たちは出発し、虚空にいるかのように、
and then all of a sudden, we're going to be attached by a thread like that, in the universe, you see, in the universe of the
そして突然、私たちは宇宙の中で、海という宇宙の中で、このように糸でつながれるでしょう。
sea.
海。
And then everything will develop, everything will come back around, like that.
そしてすべてが発展し、すべてがこのように周りに戻ってくるでしょう。
We go from a pellicle to a cord.
私たちは薄膜からコードへと向かいます。
Everything integrates like this.
すべてがこのように統合されます。
The navel is always in the right place.
へそは常に正しい位置にあります。
Sometimes, it's us who are not in the right place.
時には、私たち自身が正しい位置にいないこともあります。
We're not going to try to do anything like that, no.
私たちはこのように何かをしようとはしません、いいえ。
We come back to all this.
私たちはこれらすべてに戻ります。
Because he is connected with,
なぜなら、彼はつながっているからです。
we call the anterior sky, the posterior sky,
私たちは前方の空、後方の空と呼びます。
and everything I mean.
そして私が言いたいことすべて。
We're just going to, by putting ourselves there,
私たちはただ、そこに身を置くことで、
simply put ourselves on this reference
ただこの基準に身を置き、
and let's see how the body organizes itself.
体がどのように自ら組織化するかを見守るだけです。
You know, you will have to learn to recognize in practice, all of a sudden, all of a sudden, a process can be established.
ご存知のように、実践の中で、突然、突然、あるプロセスが始まる可能性があることを認識することを学ぶ必要があります。
be established.
始まる。
And that, you have to accompany it, because it's health that starts to work.
そして、それに寄り添う必要があります。なぜなら、それは健康が働き始めるからです。
You have to accompany it.
それに寄り添う必要があります。
We are hypnotized by the eyes.
私たちは目に催眠術をかけられています。
We are attracted by this, attracted by that.
私たちはこれに惹かれ、あれに惹かれます。
And there, I propose to you, in the work we are going to do with embryology, this biodynamic
そして、ここで私が提案するのは、発生学、このバイオダイナミクスで行う作業において、
it's...
それは...
I saw you, but I'm not leaving with you.
あなたを見たけど、あなたとは一緒に行かない。
I recognize, no, no, I saw you, I saw you, but I stay on health.
私は認識しています、いやいや、あなたを見ました、見ましたよ、でも私は健康に留まります。
I remain in the dynamic of health.
私は健康のダイナミクスの中に留まります。
I am on the health fulcrum.
私は健康の全乗組員です。
I stay on it.
私はそれに留まります。
I would like to share a short film by an Aikido master with you.
アルキドゥの達人の短い映画を皆さんと共有したいと思います。
There are two, three little things.
いくつか小さなことがあります。
We talked earlier about the notion of space, the notion of unity, you
先ほど、空間の概念、統一の概念について話しましたね、
see, and the notion of globality.
そして全体性の概念です。
the notion also
また、その概念も
a little bit
少しばかり
of harmony
調和の
of things like that
そのようなことの
you make a gesture
ジェスチャーをします
it's that
それは
you take a baby
赤ちゃんを抱き上げることです
I explain
説明します
as if you were taking
まるであなたが抱き上げるかのように
in fact you take a space
実際には空間を抱き上げます
you don't take a baby like that
赤ちゃんをこのように抱き上げるのではなく
you take a baby like that
赤ちゃんをこのように抱き上げます
You really take up all the space.
あなたは本当にすべての空間を抱きしめます。
What I want to open up to you is this notion of space.
私が皆さんに開示したいのは、この空間の概念です。
Because we're going to work with points of silence.
なぜなら、私たちは沈黙の点を使って作業するからです。
We're going to look for fulcrums in the body.
私たちは体の中の支点を探しに行きます。
But there are different depths in the silence that need to be laid down.
しかし、横たわるべき沈黙には異なる深さがあります。
There is a silence where there are first ones,
最初の沈黙があり、
and then there are deeper and deeper silences,
そして、ますます深くなる沈黙があり、
which are also connected to spaces.
それらも空間と関連しています。
It's as if we're going to have to...
まるで私たちがそうしなければならないかのように...
become aware of the space of the body
体の空間を意識する
become aware of the space, of this energy
このエネルギーの空間を意識する
that is a bit around me
私の周りにあるもの
become aware of the room
部屋を意識する
also become aware
また、意識する
really of space
本当に空間を
and if we manage little by little
そして、もし私たちが少しずつ到達できるなら
to this depth
この深さに
you will see that there are qualities
品質があることがわかるでしょう
is that said?
これは言えますか？
qualities of silence
沈黙の品質
that are different
異なるものであり、
and we will try little by little
私たちは少しずつ、
in the work that we will gradually
これから一緒に少しずつ
start doing together,
始める作業の中で、
to go and find this quality of silence.
その沈黙の質を探し求めるでしょう。
Because the body needs
なぜなら、身体は
this fulcrum,
その支点、
this point of silence
その沈黙の点が必要だからです。
to bring about a transformation.
変容を生み出すために。
It's easy English.
英語では簡単です。
What is he doing there?
彼はそこで何をしていますか？
He brings his consciousness, his mind, into his center of gravity.
彼は意識、精神を重心に戻しています。
So he's there, he even makes an upward movement.
だから彼はそこにいて、高い動きさえしています。
He feels his energy here.
彼はここで自分のエネルギーを感じています。
it's an important energy center
それは重要なエネルギーセンターです。
we will also see it purely on a biological level, we have the spirit
生物学的な観点からも、私たちはそれを見るでしょう。
that gathers this energy here
このエネルギーをここに集めます。
he refocuses
彼は自分自身を再集中させます。
in his vital energy
彼の生命エネルギーの中に。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
who have no idea what you're trying to give them.
あなたが彼らに与えようとしているものを理解していない人たちです。
Is it possible to take a group of them
彼らの中からグループを選び出し、
and present them with this totally different sense of
全く異なる価値観の感覚を彼らに提示することは可能でしょうか？
values?
価値観？
Is it possible?
それは可能でしょうか？
First, we make sure that non-fighting is not avoiding fighting.
まず、非戦闘が戦闘を避けることではないことを確認します。
Suppose violence comes this way, if you go
もし暴力がこのように来た場合、もしあなたが
that way, you are avoiding, whereas if
そのように行けば、あなたは避けていることになりますが、
you
あなたが
go opposite.
反対方向に行けば。
you will resist.
あなたは抵抗するでしょう。
So non-fighting
だから非戦闘とは、
is that you don't have to avoid,
避ける必要がない、
you don't have to resist,
抵抗する必要がない、
so how can you do it?
ではどうすればいいのでしょうか？
You should know
あなたは知っているべきです。
how you stay where you are.
あなたが今いる場所にどう留まるか。
You are here,
あなたはここにいます。
you stay where you are.
あなたは今いる場所に留まります。
And how do you do it?
では、どうすればいいのでしょうか？
You do it with this perception
この知覚を使って
of space.
空間の。
That's a bit.
これは少し。
and he remains without the actor
そして彼はアトレールなしで残る
okay, try the sharing
よし、共有を試してみて
when I lay him down, I am seeing
彼を寝かせるとき、私は自分自身を見ている
and I see the time of the actor
そして私はアトレールの時間を見る
and this time of the actor
そしてこのアトレールの時間
it's the correct one
それが正しい
and then
そしてその後
And if you want more, you do this.
もっと欲しければ、そうする。
So every time you stop.
だから、止まるたびに。
Okay, you stopped.
よし、止まった。
And you stopped.
そして止まった。
It's stopped.
止まった。
Okay, so...
よし、じゃあ...
So each time you try to stop
だから、止まろうとするたびに
with perception.
知覚をもって。
Now next, you must know how to move without
次に、動かずに動く方法を知らなければならない。
moving.
動くこと。
This means that you are the body without being
それは、あなたが脳なしで体であるという意味だ。
the brain.
あなたは脳だ。
And here, it means that you are the brain in space.
そしてここでは、それはあなたが空間の中の脳であるという意味だ。
You are here, in space.
あなたはここにいる、空間の中に。
So, this perception of space cannot move.
だから、この空間の知覚は動くことができない。
So, it's here.
だから、それはここにある。
So, this means that you are the brain.
だから、それはあなたが脳であるという意味だ。
So I don't stop, I don't stop here, and now I'm
だから私は止まらない、ここで止まらない、そして今私は
just going to keep this space.
この空間を維持するだけだ。
Which means there's no fighting.
それは戦いがないという意味だ。
If we are there, if we are there, if we are there, it is fighting.
もし私たちがそこにいるなら、もし私たちがそこにいるなら、もし私たちがそこにいるなら、それは戦いだ。
If we are there, it is there, it is there, it is there.
もし私たちがそこにいるなら、それはそこだ、それはそこだ、それはそこだ。
This space does not stop.
この空間は止まらない。
It's true, it's true.
それは本当だ、それは本当だ。
Subtitling
字幕
ST' 501
ST' 501
I cannot move others without
私は他人を動かすことはできません。
moving others.
他人を動かさずに。
Okay, so we're going to practice.
では、練習しましょう。
If I want to move his body, maybe I can.
もし私が彼の体を動かしたいなら、できるかもしれません。
But he can't move.
しかし、彼は動けません。
So now, I'm going to move the others.
では、今から他の人を動かします。
Moving means there's a space in which his body is, okay,
動かすということは、彼の体が存在する空間があるということです。
and so move the space without moving his body, okay, that
だから、彼の体を動かさずに空間を動かすのです。
means here, just take the space, this
つまり、ここでは空間を捉えるだけで、
is move others without moving, okay, that's all right.
これは動かさずに他人を動かすということです。
You have something up there?
何か上にありますか？
Now, if I'm going to go to the next slide, I'm going to go to the next slide.
さて、次のスライドに進みます。
If I want to turn you like this, it becomes conflict.
もし私があなたをこのように回したいなら、それは衝突になります。
So, like a baby, there is a space, and I take all of the space.
だから、赤ちゃんのように、空間があり、私は空間全体を捉えます。
So, that means the baby doesn't turn, just all
つまり、赤ちゃんは回らず、ただ空間全体を回すのです。
of the space.
空間全体を。
That's what you do when you baby them.
赤ちゃんを扱うとき、あなたはそうします。
Babies don't turn like that.
赤ちゃんはそんな風には回りません。
I see that.
それは分かります。
So you can do that even with others?
では、他の人にも同じことができますか？
...
...
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
It's easier, isn't it?
もっと簡単ですよね？
Yes, it's easier.
はい、もっと簡単です。
Subtitles by Radio-Canada
カナダ放送協会字幕
How can we move without destroying?
破壊せずにどうやって動かすことができるでしょうか？
So, if we move space, we can move this person
だから、もし私たちが空間を動かすなら、私たちはその人を
with respect.
敬意をもって動かすことができます。
That is to say, we do not destroy this person.
つまり、私たちはその人を破壊しないということです。
So, this is Aikido.
これが合気道です。
In Aikido, you should treat all people, in all circumstances, with respect.
合気道では、どんな状況でもすべての人を敬意をもって扱うべきです。
When people are in love, they say "Oh, hello!"
人々が恋をしているとき、彼らは「ああ、こんにちは！」と言います。
But when there are people who are not in love, they start
しかし、恋をしていない人々がいるとき、彼らは
to fight against relationships.
関係と戦い始めます。
That is to say, they do not maintain relationships with others in all circumstances.
つまり、彼らはどんな状況でも他人との関係を維持しないということです。
So, both hands.
だから、両手で。
If I want him to be from him, he is from him, there is no respect.
彼がいてほしいなら、彼がいます。尊敬はありません。
So, there is a space here.
だから、ここにスペースがあります。
There is a space here.
ここにスペースがあります。
It's good, it's good, it's
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。
good.
いいよ。
Yes, it's good.
はい、いいですよ。
Let's go, let's go.
さあ、行こう、さあ、行こう。
Yes, of course.
はい、もちろんです。
So...
だから...
I see.
なるほど。
Yes, that's it.
はい、そうです。
I'm going to put you behind.
後ろに置きますね。
Let's go.
さあ、行こう。
Okay, try.
はい、試してみてください。
Try.
試してみてください。
An axis, a cattle.
軸、家畜。
I have a first zone.
最初のゾーンがあります。
A first zone that can respond to the body.
体に反応できる最初のゾーン。
We'll say to the physical body.
肉体と言いましょう。
First zone.
最初のゾーン。
To zone A.
ゾーンAへ。
And then around you, you emit a radiation,
そして、あなたの周りには、放射線、
a warmth, a space around
熱、あなたの周りの空間、
you.
があります。
And then there's the room you're in, and
そして、あなたがいる部屋があり、
then there's the horizon.
そして、地平線があります。
we're going to look for
私たちは探しに行きます
in each space, little by little, we'll start from the beginning
それぞれの空間で、少しずつ、最初から始めます
to find this point of silence, when I enter a room
この沈黙の点を見つけるために、部屋に入るとき、
very quickly I look for how I position myself in this room
私はすぐに、この部屋で自分がどのように位置しているかを探します。
how the space around me is, how I can position myself
私の周りの空間がどうなっているか、どのように自分を配置できるか、
to be well, me in the practice of embryology that we are going to do
快適であるために、私がこれから行う胚発生学の実践では、
we will work with these spaces, the body will reorient itself
これらの空間と協力します。体は再調整されます。
in relation to this space. The space is there. It's just about being in adequacy.
この空間に関して。空間はそこにあります。それはただ適合することです。